Andrew Eskridge

ENGINEERING MANAGER

Profile

Engineering Manager with experience directing teams of software engineers and quality assurance analysts. Maintains a highly effective communication style and utilizes it to build trust within my team and with other teams. History of managing multiple products and delivering great results on time.

Employment History

Chief Technical Officer, Cenergistic, Dallas

2018 - 2022

- Created products that doubled the amount of square footage our employees could manage
- Built out a team of developers and QA within six months of starting
 - Managed a team of 10 reports
- Shifted infrastructure from bare virtual machines to containerized applications hosted on AWS Elastic Container Service
 - This modernization reduced costs by 50%

Project Leader, Beck Technology, Dallas

2016 - 2018

- Lead a team of two developers
- Developed user stories and worked through the implementation with my team
- Implemented a cloud based 3D model viewer into the desktop application
 - Also created a 3D model comparison tool to compare multiple versions of a model

Senior Software Engineer, ProviderScience, Dallas

2015 - 2016

- Designed and implemented a predicting system capable of determining the optimal number of personnel needed to staff a pharmacy
 - Implemented the solution using a Decision Forest

Senior Software Engineer, Gwynn Group, Inc, Dallas

2015 - 2015

- Created a forecast engine that could predict any time-series metric
 - Used Triple Exponential Smoothing as it reduced false alarms by 20% compared to other forecast algorithms
- Designed and implemented many custom visualizations to help clients understand and explore extremely large datasets

Software Developer, Allegro, Dallas

2013 - 2015

- Rewrote the build process using MSBuild and C#
 - Resulted in a speed up of the build time by 4x, going from hours to minutes
- Developed new Business Intelligence Portal using C#, MVC5, and SQL Server
 - Created over twenty BI reports using Tableau

Education

Computer Science, University of Texas, Austin

Details

Dallas United States (850) 341-9336 andy@eskridge.dev

Links

eskridge.dev

Skills

Leadership

People Management

Typescript

JavaScript

React

React Native

Amazon AWS

DevOps

Predictive Analytics

Machine Learning

Algorithms

Elasticsearch